Elochukwu Aroh

Software Developer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: elochukwuaroh@gmail.com

Address: 555 Keenleyside Street R2K3P6, Winnipeg, Manitoba

Phone: +1587-357-2325

Link: Personal Portfolio Website: https://elochukwuaroh.com -----LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elochukwu-aroh-b5a71617b/ ------GitHub: https://github.com/aroh-elochukwu ------

OBJECTIVE

A passionate Software Developer, with about 3 years of experience building and maintaining mobile and web applications. Eager to join your challenging work environment, utilizing my technical skills in creating responsive, user-friendly, and customer-oriented projects with laser focus attention to specifications.

EXPERIENCE

Winnipeg, Manitoba

Jan 2023 - Present

Software Developer

UpWork Inc.

· Accept freelance contract projects to deliver on Client Application design needs with today's best technology.

Winnipeg, Manitoba

Oct 2022 - Present

Software Developer Intern

Bit Space Develoment

- Collaborated with Colleagues on projects to create feature updates.
- Worked with project managers, fellow developers, and quality assurance to deliver on customer needs.
- · Researching, designing, implementing, upgrading and managing software programs.
- Collaborated efficiently with team members to deliver on organizational goals.

Asaba, Delta State, Nigeria

Apr 2017 - Apr 2021

Data Analyst

Delta State Contributory Health Commission

- · Performing analysis to assess the quality of data.
- · Preparation and presentation of organizational data charts and projections.
- The verification of enrollee status for payment of claims of services rendered by Healthcare Providers.
- · Enrollee and Healthcare facility database management, ensure data accuracy and integrity.
- · Selected as one of 3 Baseline Enumerators for the Warri North Local Government Area to research and document the state of primary Healthcare delivery in the region. This facilitated in making my stateowned health insurance scheme the highest ranked in the country.

Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

Apr 2021 - Jan 2022

Sales Associate

I-Pull U-Pull Auto Parts, Canada

- · Served as one of the frontline brand representatives welcoming and directing customers around store merchandise, operating the cash register, and maintaining floor appearance.
- · Maintained the status of the company's highest grossing sales personnel with impeccable customer service and devotion to duty.

Warri, Delta state, Nigeria

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

Hardware maintenance and installations personnel (Intern)

Hi-tech Distributors. Computers and Office supplies

- · Hardware maintenance and repairs
- · Installation of equipment purchased by costumers

EDUCATION

Winnipeg, Manitoba

2022 - Present

Diploma Software Development

Manitoba Institute of Trades and Technology

Benin City, Nigeria

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

BSc Computer Science Benson Idahosa University

Ibo (Nigerian language)

SKILLS

English

Advanced

Very good

LANGUAGES

ReactJS C#

Angular.js

Pro-efficiency in Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint

Time Management SQL

Javascript ASP.Net Core

Object Oriented programming

Team player

Git

PROJECTS

N.B All projects host on my personal website https://elochukwuaroh.com

Elo-TV: This was a page built with React.js using the 'moviedbapi' to display show information from the big movie streaming platforms.

Expense-Chart: An application built with React.js that allows a user to add daily expenses thereby creating a description and bar chart on a monthly basis.

Tic Tac Toe Game: A beautiful user interface designed with React.js of the popular game.

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Scrum Foundations certification from Scrum Alliance, Oct 2022

Project Management Course, July 2016

Cyber-Security Ethics in Health Information Management by the National Health Insurance Scheme, November 2019

Health Services Standard Quality Control training by PharnAccess Group, March 2019

Teamwork and Work Place Ethics by Streamline Group, April 2019 Workplace Hazardous Material Information System Certified (GHS 2015), December 2021

REFERENCES



Available on request